(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine
and today we're talking about
something that I haven't
actually seen in a long time,
but it's very common in the
States, especially in suburban areas.
- That's right, we're
gonna get a subscription
as the title of the lesson says.
So we're gonna subscribe to
magazines, newspapers, stuff like that.
- Right, so there's a guy coming
around to everyone's houses
and he's offering different
magazine subscriptions.
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue
and we'll be back in a moment
to talk about what's going on.
(upbeat music)
- Good afternoon ma'am, my name is Mike
and I'm selling subscriptions
to all sorts of periodicals.
- No, thank you, I'm not interested.
- Please ma'am, if you could
spare five minutes of your time,
I'm sure we could find
something that could interest you.
- I wish I could, but I
have to walk the dog
and finish cooking,
so if you'd excuse me.
We have a great variety of
magazines all about cooking.
This one, for example, is the buy month's
the publication with recipes
from all over the world.
- Wow, wow, that would be kind of useful.
Do you have any other cooking magazines?
- Sure do, this one is
a quarterly publication,
but each issue has over
200 colored pages of
recipes and also many
home decorating ideas.
- Wow, this is nice.
Okay, sign me up for both publications.
- You mentioned you have a dog, most pet
owners sign up for this weekly newsletter
that has information on dog
care, pet shops and even pet sitters.
- That's exactly what I needed.
What else do you have?
- Well, I also have.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back,
so as you saw, Mike is,
well, not very excited to
be selling subscriptions,
but he has magazines about
almost everything, I think.
- That's right, and he's actually
a pretty good sales person
because it sounds like this customer
is going to buy quite a few magazines.
- Exactly, and so he
used a lot of interesting
vocabulary related to
magazines and subscriptions,
so let's take a look at those
now in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- Okay, so this first
word is one that we've
already said a couple
of times in today's lesson.
This is the topic of the lesson.
The word is subscription.
- Okay, so if you get a subscription,
that means that you are paying money
to receive something every
month, every week, et cetera.
- That's right, so the time is fixed.
You'd like you said, it could be weekly.
The time could change, but
basically you have a promise
that after you pay this money,
you'll receive something periodically,
and so there are many things
that you could have a subscription
for, not just magazines, news
papers come in subscriptions.
- That's right, or maybe
you pay for satellite TV.
That's a subscription,
so you pay every month,
and you receive channels,
like lots of channels.
- Exactly, or hopefully, English pot,
you receive buy subscription,
or you pay the subscription fee.
- Exactly, so with English pot, you
subscribe, that would be the verb.
A subscription is the noun.
You subscribe to a service,
like a newspaper magazine,
and you receive the magazine
or the service every month,
every week, every day, depending
on what the subscription is like.
- Okay, and so because subscriptions come
at different time frames, so for example,
in English pot, we have
lessons three times a week.
Newspapers are oftentimes every day.
They come in different periods of time,
so we call these kinds of
publications periodic calls.
- Okay, so for example,
as you said, a newspaper,
it comes every day, that's the
period of time, so it's a periodical.
The same as a magazine, sometimes they
are weekly, sometimes they are monthly.
- Is a book a periodical, pop quiz?
- No.
- Okay.
- No, because you only get it once.
- Right, so basically a
periodical has to be something,
I guess, that comes out every so often
a new version, a new addition, right?
- It's continually updating.
- Okay, so that is
periodicals and subscriptions.
Now moving on to when he
was trying to sell the magazines,
he said, we have a great
variety of magazines
all about cooking,
so what is a variety?
- Variety is a great word.
It's a word I personally
am very, a very big fan of.
I like to have many choices to choose from,
so variety means something
that has many options.
For example, at the grocery
store, there's a great variety of food.
There are apples and
crackers and cakes and wine,
so variety means there are
many different kinds of something.
- Okay, so many choices,
so if you go to a bookstore,
you can find a variety of books
and magazines, for example.
All right, now moving on to again, when
we're talking about the period of time,
how often she's going to
get this cooking magazine,
the one that he's showing
her is a bi-monthly publication.
So what exactly does it mean if
she receives a magazine bi-monthly?
- Okay, so this is a bit confusing in
English, bi-monthly has two meanings,
but what's important is the word bi
here, or the prefix bi, that means two.
- Okay.
- Okay, so we could say bi-monthly,
bi-weekly, bi-annually, these all mean two.
So in this case, we're talking about something
that I receive two times every month.
- Okay, or it can be that you
get it once every two months.
- Okay, so that might be confusing.
- Right.
- In the first case, let's just say that it's the month of October,
and I have this great
subscription to a magazine,
so in October, I will
receive it two times.
- Exactly, so you get it twice, or it could
also mean that you receive the magazine
in October, and then you
don't receive another magazine
until December, so it's
a bi-monthly publication.
- Every two months, every two months.
- Right, so this is very confusing
for us, it's probably confusing for you,
but if you see this word
bi-monthly, or bi-weekly,
you should ask the person who's offering
the subscription, what kind they mean?
Is it every month two times,
or is it every other month?
- All right, so exactly, just
remember the prefix bi means two,
and then if it's bi-monthly,
bi-annual, bi-weekly,
you have to more or less
make sure that they specify
what they mean, because they can mean both,
and that's how ambiguous this word is.
- It is, but the next one, the next word
we have for you is not nearly as confusing.
It's a very, very common
word in both periodicals and
sales, but also in marketing
and business as well.
- Right, we're talking
about a quarterly publication
or something that comes
out once every quarter.
- Right, so if you think about a year,
a year has 12 months, a
quarter of a year is three months.
So the first quarter is
January, if you have very much.
- Exactly, so a quarterly publication means
that you will get a magazine
four times in one year.
Okay, we could also
talk about quarterly sales.
This quarter, our business did very
well, but last quarter was not so good.
So quarter means three months at a time.
- Exactly, and for our last
word on language takeaway
today, we are talking
about a weekly newsletter.
So weekly is pretty straightforward.
You receive it once every week.
- That's right, so weekly
publications are very common.
What is a newsletter?
- A newsletter is important in periodicals
because it's not a magazine,
but it's not a letter either.
It's basically short update,
a couple of pages maybe,
or even one page that's on
a piece of paper that gives
you information about a
group or a club or a community.
For example, we could say the English
pot newsletter comes out quarterly.
- Exactly, maybe in your offices, you
receive your company's newsletter.
So usually, some companies
will come out with a monthly
or a quarterly newsletter
where if you have many offices
or many branches all over
the country or the world,
then you will receive
updates or news about what's
going on in other places
within your same company.
- That's right, so these are very useful
for communication across the company.
You can tell some people
in your New York office
that in Los Angeles, we have a
new cafeteria or a new employee.
- Exactly, so that is what a
newsletter is basically for.
I think it's time now for us to listen
to the dialogue again, and
we'll be back to talk to you
with four key phrases on
Fluency Builder right after this.
(upbeat music)
- Good afternoon, ma'am.
My name is Mike, and I'm selling
subscriptions to all sorts of periodicals.
- No, thank you, I'm not interested.
- Please, ma'am, if you could
spare five minutes of your time,
I'm sure we could find
something that could interest you.
- I wish I could, but I
have to walk the dog
and finish cooking,
so if you'd excuse me.
- We have a great variety of
magazines all about cooking.
This one, for example,
is a bi-monthly
publication with recipes
from all over the world.
- Wow, wow, that would be kind of useful.
Do you have any other cooking magazines?
- Sure do, this one is
a quarterly publication,
but each issue has
over 200 color pages of
recipes and also many
home decorating ideas.
- Wow, this is nice.
Okay, sign me up for both publications.
- You mentioned you have a dog, most pet
owners sign up for this weekly newsletter
that has information on dog
care, pet shops, and even pet sitters.
- That's exactly what I needed.
What else do you have?
- Well, I also have...
(upbeat music)
- All right, so now we have some sentences
or ways that you can say
things on fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
Okay, this first phrase is very,
very common among sales
and salespeople, because
basically it's a way to be polite
and to ask someone to
listen to you for a little while.
The salesperson says, if you could
spare five minutes of your time.
- Okay, so let's start with that part.
If you could spare.
So to spare something means
do you have something extra?
Is it, do you have enough of it?
- Yeah, so I could say, can you spare $5?
I forgot my wallet at home.
So that means do you have
an extra $5 I could borrow?
- Okay, very good.
So if you asking someone to
spare five minutes of their time,
you're asking them to give
you five minutes of their time.
- That's right, so if you
could spare a second
or if you could spare five minutes of
your time, I would like to talk to you.
- Okay, so it's a very polite way
to ask someone for their time.
Now, for our next phrase,
the woman is also very polite.
She says, you know what, I have to
walk the dog, I have to finish cooking.
So if you would excuse me, she's
basically saying, no, in a very polite way.
If you could excuse me, I've gotta go.
- So this is kind of a very indirect,
but polite way of saying,
I'm sorry, I can't stay,
I gotta go, or I can't
really talk to you right now.
- That's right, even if
you're at a party, for example,
and you're talking to somebody, but you
don't really wanna talk to them anymore,
you could say, it was nice talking
to you, if you could excuse me.
- Mm-hmm, okay. - If I can leave now.
- Okay, so you can say,
if you could excuse me,
or if you would excuse me, both
forms are pretty much the same.
Okay, and what about when
she actually is convinced
about the magazine,
she says, wow, this is nice.
Okay, sign me up for both publications.
- Okay, sign me up, this means
I would like a subscription.
Okay, that means I
would like you to take my
information and I will
give you some money.
But this is also a really
nice phrase in English,
because it means I wanna
do this, I'm interested.
- So if you would use
this in another context,
for example, a group of
friends are going to the movies.
- I say, oh, sign me up, I wanna go.
I heard that movie was awesome.
- Okay, very good, so sign
me up is like, include me,
I wanna go to, or I'm part
of it of whatever you're doing.
- Exactly.
- Okay, so that's all the
phrases we have for you today.
I think they're really
good, they're not specific
for this circumstance
of getting a subscription.
As we saw, we can use
them in many other situations.
So I think we should go
back, listen to the dialogue
for the last time, and we'll
be back to talk a little bit more.
(upbeat music)
- Good afternoon, ma'am, my name is Mike
and I'm selling subscriptions
to all sorts of periodicals.
- No, thank you, I'm not interested.
- Please, ma'am, if you could
spare five minutes of your time,
I'm sure we could find
something that could interest you.
- I wish I could, but I
have to walk the dog
and finish cooking,
so if you'd excuse me.
- We have a great variety of
magazines all about cooking.
This one, for example, is the buy money
for publication with recipes
from all over the world.
- Wow, wow, that would be kind of useful.
Do you have any other cooking magazines?
- Sure do, this one is
a quarterly publication,
but each issue has
over 200 color pages of
recipes and also many
home decorating ideas.
- Wow, this is nice.
- Okay, sign me up for both publications.
- You mentioned you have a dog.
Most pet owners sign up
for this weekly newsletter
that has information on dog
care, pet shops, and even pet sitters.
- That's exactly what I needed.
What else do you have?
- Well, I also have.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so subscriptions,
periodicals, all this
is very common as you
said in the United States.
People get them through
the mail every month, right?
- That's right, and I have to
say, it's changing now, you know?
We used to get subscriptions
at home when I was a kid.
We'd have magazine subscriptions
and even a newspaper subscription.
But these days, people
are doing more and
more on the internet,
so you don't see the guy
with the subscriptions
coming from, you know,
going from door to
door to sell you this.
You do it yourself on the
internet, so it's pretty common.
That way, do you have
any web subscriptions?
- Uh, no, no, no, I don't, I haven't
signed up for any periodicals on the web.
I do receive the newspaper every day.
And that's about, it's kind
of hard to receive magazines
where we are, but I am
a big fan of magazines
like National Geographic
or Popular Mechanics.
- I had that when I was a kid.
My grandmother
would always give us a
subscription to National
Geographic for Christmas.
- It's a very good
magazine and it's so colorful,
full of pictures and
really interesting articles,
not only about animals, but
about the world in general.
So it's really cool.
- That's right, and they always give you a
map that you could take out and open up.
And it was the best part
of the whole magazine.
- Exactly.
So actually, I really
enjoy having subscriptions
to periodicals, magazines,
newspapers, not a big
fan of newsletters or
things on the internet.
I kind of like to hold it, hold a magazine
or take it with me if I'm on a trip.
- Yeah, I totally agree.
- So yeah, but I think many
of our listeners may have
a subscription to their local
newspaper, local magazines
or maybe as you said,
internet subscriptions.
I know some people sign up
for the Harvard Business Review
that's available online or even I think
the New York Times has an online platform.
- They do, they do, so
you should let us know.
What subscriptions do you have?
What periodicals do you like to read?
Our website, of course, is EnglishPod.com.
You can also purchase a subscription there.
We hope to see you on the
website and until next time.
All right, bye.